Working Inventory of the Robert E. Marshak Papers, 1947-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Tenth International Conference on High Energy Physics. Rochester, New York, August 25-September 1, 1960.
  - Scientific program. General. (Box-folder 4-1)
  - Scientific program. Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Administration. General. (Box-folder 4-3)
  - Administration. Organizing committee. (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Administration. Pre-conference-Theoretical Institute. (Box-folder 4-5)
  - Administration. Post-conference tour. (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Administration. Translators. (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Administration. Transportation for foreign attendees. (Box-folder 4-8)
  - Administration. Women's programs. (Box-folder 4-9)
  - Public events-banquet. (Box-folder 4-10)
  - Post-conference correspondence. (Box-folder 4-11)
  - Sociological matters. International Atomic Energy Association. (Box-folder 4-12)
  - Sociological matters. MATS. (Box-folder 4-13)
  - Sociological matters. Russian and East European scientists. (Box-folder 4-14)
  - Sociological matters. Visas. (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Public relations. Requests for information. (Box-folder 4-16)
  - Public relations. Press releases. (Box-folder 4-17)
  - Public relations. Newspaper and magazine articles. (Box-folder 4-18)
  - Photographs. (Box-folder 4-19)
- Eleventh International Conference on High Energy Physics. CERN, Geneva, Switzerland, July 4-11, 1962.
  - Invitations. American Advisory Committee- US invitees. Robert E. Marshak correspondence. (Box-folder 4-20)
  - American Advisory Committee-US invitees. William A. Jamison correspondence. (Box-folder 4-21)
  - American Advisory Committee-US invitees. Edwin H. McMillan correspondence. (Box-folder 4-22)
  - Lists of Western invitees. (Box-folder 4-23)
  - Scientific program. (Box-folder 4-24)
  - Administration. (Box-folder 4-25)
  - Public relations. Correspondence of William A. Jamison. (Box-folder 4-26)
- Twelfth International Conference on High Energy Physics. Dubna, USSR, August 5-11, 1964.
  - Advisory Committee. (Box-folder 4-27)
  - Scientific program. (Box-folder 4-28)
- Thirteenth International Conference on High Energy Physics. Berkeley, California, August 31-September 7, 1966.
  - United States invitations. (Box-folder 4-29)
  - Foreign invitations. (Box-folder 4-30)
  - List of invited delegates. (Box-folder 4-31)
- International Theoretical Physics Conference on Particles and Fields. Rochester, New York, August 28-September 1, 1967.
  - Institutional sponsorship. (Box-folder 4-32)
  - United States invitations. (Box-folder 4-33)
  - Foreign invitations. (Box-folder 4-34)
  - Soviet and Eastern bloc invitations. (Box-folder 4-35)
  - Invitees-lists. (Box-folder 4-36)
  - Soviet and Eastern bloc. (Box-folder 4-37)
  - Atomic Energy Commission-correspondence. (Box-folder 4-38)
  - Department of State-correspondence. (Box-folder 4-39)
  - Scientific program. Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-40)
  - Scientific program. Program copies and notes. (Box-folder 4-41)
  - Administration. Budget. (Box-folder 4-42)
  - Administration. Local arrangements. (Box-folder 4-43)
  - Administration. Women's program. (Box-folder 4-44)
  - Administration. Travel reimbursements. (Box-folder 4-45)
  - Public events. Banquet. (Box-folder 4-46)
  - Banquet speaker-Glenn Seaborg. (Box-folder 4-47)
  - Post-conference correspondence. (Box-folder 4-48)
  - Public relations. General. (Box-folder 4-49)
  - Public relations. Requests for information. (Box-folder 4-50)
  - Public relations. Press releases. (Box-folder 4-51)
  - Public relations. Newspaper articles. (Box-folder 4-52)
  - Proceedings. General correspondence. (Box-folder 4-53)
  - Proceedings. Correspondence. Publisher-John Wiley and Sons. (Box-folder 4-54)
  - Proceedings. Correspondence. Sales and distribution. (Box-folder 4-55)
  - Photographs. (Box-folder 4-56)
- Fourteenth International Conference on High Energy Physics. Vienna, Austria, August 28-September 5, 1968.
  - Invitations-United States. Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Scientific program. Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Scientific program. Program copies. (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Selected comments from visitors. (Box-folder 5-4)
- Fifteenth International Conference on High Energy Physics. Kiev, USSR, 1970.
  - Invitations. Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-5)
  - Israeli delegates. Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-6)
- US-Soviet Scientific Relations, 1956-1966.
  - Correspondence, documents, note, 1956. (Box-folder 5-7)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes, 1958. (Box-folder 5-8)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes, 1959. (Box-folder 5-9)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes. Includes materials on a trip by an American delegation to the USSR under the McCone-Emelyanov Agreement, 1960. (Box-folder 5-10)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes, 1961-1962. (Box-folder 5-11)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes, 1963. (Box-folder 5-12)
  - Correspondence, documents, notes, 1965-1966. (Box-folder 5-13)
- International Union of Pure and Applied Physics (IUPAP) 1953-1967.
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954. (Box-folder 5-14)
  - Documents and minutes, 1953-1954. (Box-folder 5-15)
  - Correspondence, 1956. (Box-folder 5-16)
  - Documents and minutes. Includes materials on the creation of the IUPAP Commission on High Energy Physics, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 5-17)
  - Correspondence, 1958. (Box-folder 5-18)
  - Documents and minutes, 1958. (Box-folder 5-19)
  - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 5-20)
  - Documents and minutes 1959. (Box-folder 5-21)
  - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 5-22)
  - Documents and minutes, 1960. (Box-folder 5-23)
  - Correspondence, 1961. (Box-folder 5-24)
  - Documents and minutes, 1961. (Box-folder 5-25)
  - Correspondence. General correspondence, 1962. (Box-folder 5-26)
  - Correspondence. Letter of Robert E. Marshak asking for advice on holding future International High Energy Physics Conferences and responses. (Box-folder 5-27)
  - Documents and minutes, 1962. (Box-folder 5-28)
  - Correspondence 1963. (Box-folder 5-29)
  - Documents and minutes, 1963. (Box-folder 5-30)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1972. (Box-folder 5-31)
  - Documents and minutes, 1964-1972. (Box-folder 5-32)
- Miscellaneous, 1970-1990.
  - Oral history interview with Robert E. Marshak done by Charles Weiner of the American Institute of Physics, 1970. (Box-folder 5-33)
  - Robert E. Marshak, "The Rochester Conferences: The Rise of International Cooperation in High Energy Physics." Bulletin of Atomic Scientists, June 1970. (Box-folder 5-34)
  - Robert E. Marshak, "Scientific Impact of the First Decade of the 'Rochester' Conferences." A paper given by Marshak at a symposium on "Particle Physics in the 1950s: Pions to Quarks." Fermilab, 1985 Conference Proceedings, edited by L. Brown and L. Hoddeson. (Box-folder 5-35)
  - Robert E. Marshak, "Contribution of the First Decade of the 'Rochester' Conferences to the restructuring of Particle Physics (1950-1960)." A paper presented by Marshak at a conference on "The Restructuring of the Physical Sciences in Europe and the United States, 1945-60" in Rome during September 1988; to be published in the conference proceedings edited by M. De Maria and M. Grilli. (Box-folder 5-36)
  - Robert E. Marshak, "The Khrushchev Detente and Emerging Internationalism in Particle Physics." Physics Today, January 1990. (Box-folder 5-37)
  - Microfiche copy of the collection. (Box-folder 5-38)
- Box A1
  - A-AMD, including: (Box-folder A1-1)
    - 1. Abashian - misc. correspondence to/from.
    - 2. P.T. Abraham - misc. correspondence to/from.
    - 3. African Mission - correspondence to/from Salam, S. Husain, etc.; also articles.
    - 4. AIA - Accuracy in Academia - articles, newspaper copies; and papers written.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - council meetings, correspondence. (Box-folder A1-2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - budgets, proposed software policy, progress reports. (Box-folder A1-3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - recommend candidates for election '88, listing of the officers, councilors, and standing committeers. (Box-folder A1-4)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - council meetings, correspondence, etc. (Box-folder A1-5)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - correspondence. (Box-folder A1-6)
  - AAAS agendas for 1983, 1984 meetings; biographical sketches. (Box-folder A1-7)
  - AAAS agendas for 1985, 1986, 1987, etc. (Box-folder A1-8)
  - AAAS committee on scientific freedom and responsibility. (Box-folder A1-9)
- Box A2
  - 1983-84 Directory of the AAAS Consortium of Affiliates for International Programs. (Box-folder A2-1)
  - Chalk, R. - correspondence and draft papers sent by Rosemary Chalk. (Box-folder A2-2)
  - AAAS Projects and correspondence under this group; AAAS public sector programs - addresses and telephone no. of past and present congressional science and engineering fellows. (Box-folder A2-3)
  - 1990 AAAS Symposium - correspondence, articles, presentation cover sheets, etc. (Box-folder A2-4)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers - correspondence from C. L. Andrews, Chairman, William Fidler, etc. (Box-folder A1-5)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers, including: (Box-folder A1-6)
    - 1. ACLS - correspondence from Georgene B. Lovecky.
    - 2. American Philosophical Society - program for general meeting '84 '87; listing of nominations for membership '84; correspondence Randolph Klein, etc.
  - AMF-AS, including: (Box-folder A2-7)
    - 1. Arms Control Association - correspondence to/from Spurgeon M. Keeny, Jr.; article by Spurgeon Keeny; Arms Control Association Annual Report.
    - 2. Associated Universities - correspondence; reports; booklets on organization and its objectives for '63, '65, '68; etc.
  - AT-AZ - correspondence in connection with atomic sciencists, atomic development, etc. (Box-folder A2-8)
    - Notebook 1: correspondence about high energy group, etc.
  - Atomic Energy Commission - correspondence from and to various people concerning the Atomic Energy Commission. (Box-folder A2-9)
- Box B1
  - B-BES, including: (Box-folder B1-1)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: John Bailey and Robert Bacher.
    - 2. Baldo-Ceolin (correspondence).
    - 3. Bethe-correspondence to/from.
    - 4. Talks at VPI-mailing lists, letters, reports.
  - BF-BK, including: (Box-folder B1-2)
    - 1. BITNET-correspondence concerning BITNET (IBM communication network).
  - Blacksburg Workshop '79 "Weak Interactions," including: (Box-folder B1-3)
    - 1. Participants lists, correspondence, and booklet (banquet menu).
  - Workshop, including: (1980). (Box-folder B1-4)
    - 1. Letters and comments on the workshop.
    - 2. Workshop budget.
    - 3. 1982 workshop.
  - Bills, Expenditures, Purchases, etc. (Box-folder B1-5)
  - Blacksburg Workshop, including: (1983). (Box-folder B1-6)
    - 1. Mailing list, schedules, descriptions of the workshop, confirmation of reservations, etc.
  - Bohr Symposium II, including: (Box-folder B1-7)
    - 1. The Niel Bohr Symposium, reports, articles, letters of intent for support, etc.
  - BLAH-BQ, including: (Box-folder B1-8)
    - 1. Various correspondence to/from: Stephen Blaha, Gertrude Blanche, etc.
    - 2. Bonn Conference: registration forms, name lists of participants, etc.
    - 3. Book (with Sudarshan)-Marshak wrote book with Sudarshan. Includes: book review, correspondence, list of names to send book to.
    - 4. Book gifts-correspondence, donating of books, etc.
    - 5. Book orders, bills, catalogue, etc.
  - BR-BRD, including: (Box-folder B1-9)
    - 1. Various correspondence from: John Brademas, Hugh Bradner, etc.
    - 2. Branco, G.-correspondence to/from Gustavo C. Branco.
    - 3. Brazil-request, reports, articles.
  - BRE-BZ, including: (Box-folder B1-10)
    - 1. Various correspondence-Gregory Breit, D. A. Bromley.
    - 2. Brookhaven Lab-correspondence.
    - 3. Bulletin of Atomic Scientist.
- Box B2
  - CUSPEA (China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program) Record Booklet. (Box-folder B2-1)
  - 1982 CUSPEA-Correspondence and Lists. (Box-folder B2-2)
  - 1983 CUSPEA-Correspondence and Lists. (Box-folder B2-3)
  - 1984 CUSPEA-Correspondence and Lists. (Box-folder B2-4)
  - 1985 CUSPEA Record Booklet. (Box-folder B2-5)
  - 1986 CUSPEA Record Booklet. (Box-folder B2-6)
  - 1987 CUSPEA Record Booklet. (Box-folder B2-7)
  - C-CA, including: (Box-folder B2-8)
    - 1. Letters to/from: Robert Cahn; Curriculum Vitae by John Cairns, etc.
    - 2. Carnegie Institute of Technology-awards, letters, and articles.
    - 3. Calling cards-business cards.
    - 4. Carlisle, Fred-correspondence.
  - CB-CHI, including: (Box-folder B2-9)
    - 1. CEBAF (Continuous Electron Beam Accelerator Faculty).
    - 2. Cern-correspondence.
    - 3. Chang, L. N.-correspondence.
  - China Committee, including: (Box-folder B2-10)
    - 1. Correspondence, reports, etc.
  - CHJ-COLLINS, including: (Box-folder B2-11)
    - 1. Choices and Challenges (pamphlets, etc.).
    - 2. Chou, Kuang-Chao (Publications list, correspondence to/from).
    - 3. City College (letter and program).
    - 4. City University (Poster).
    - 5. Correspondence to/from: Edward Clancy, Kenneth Clark, etc.
  - CHINA, including: (Box-folder B2-12)
    - 1. Reports from China, pamphlets, etc.
    - 2. China Trip Report '81 (reports and correspondence).
  - COLM-COMN, including: (Box-folder B2-13)
    - 1. Correspondence from the Columbia Broadcast Center; Joseph Comfort, etc.
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, including: (Box-folder B2-14)
    - 1. New letters and reports.
  - Committee of Urban Program Universities (CUPU), including: (Box-folder B2-15)
    - 1. Correspondence and reports.
  - Committee on National Educational Policies in Science and Engineering-A Report. (Box-folder B2-16)
- Box C1
  - Coral Gables-correspondence concerning the Coral Gables conferences. (Box-folder C1-1)
  - International Conference on Theoretical Physics, Kyoto and Tokyo, Japan, September '53-correspondence. (Box-folder C1-2)
  - Symposium on Basic Research '59-correspondence. (Box-folder C1-3)
  - Tata Summer School '60-'61. Correspondence from Bhabha, etc.; book on the inauguration of new buildings at Tata. (Box-folder C1-4)
  - Japanese conference-correspondence to/from: N. Fukuda, Hideki Yukawa, etc. (Box-folder C1-5)
  - Misc. correspondence-to/from/about: 4th annual workshop on Novae; R. F. Sawyer, etc. (1980). (Box-folder C1-6)
  - 1981-Papers on conferences and symposiums. (Box-folder C1-7)
  - TWOGU-correspondence about the Third Workshop on Grand Unification. (Box-folder C1-8)
  - 1982-Symposiums, correspondence from Wick Haxton, Andre Bertholet, etc. (Box-folder C1-9)
  - FWOGU-Fourth Workshop on Grand Unification-participants list and registration form. (Box-folder C1-10)
  - DPF Meeting in Sante Fe. (Box-folder C1-11)
  - Wingspread-seminar schedule. (Box-folder C1-12)
  - Santa Fe Meeting-Rio Grande Institute: schedules for workshops. (Box-folder C1-13)
  - 1985-correspondence to/from Stefan Pokerski, Grzegor Bialkowski, etc. (Box-folder C1-14)
  - Japan '85-papers written by Marshak, forms from international travel requests, etc. (Box-folder C1-15)
  - June 1985 Meeting-scientific notes, correspondence from Janet Manning, etc. (Box-folder C1-16)
  - Notes on 1985 conference. (Box-folder C1-17)
  - Fermilab, May 1985-programs, correspondence, etc. (Box-folder C1-18)
  - 1986 Meeting. (Box-folder C1-19)
  - Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics (13th) 1986. (Box-folder C1-20)
  - Conferences, including: (Box-folder C1-21)
    - 1. 1987: Meetings, Symposiuim on Conversation Law in Physics.
    - 2. Landau Symposium in Copenhagen.
    - 3. Hamburg Conference of 1987-listing of participants, and scientific notes.
    - 4. 1987-schedule for tentative workshop.
    - 5. Summer 1987, Bristol: notes and papers concering trips to United Kingdom, London, etc.
    - 6. 1988-miscellaneous correspondence to/from: I. M. Khalatnikov, Frank Kockling, etc.
    - 7. Rome Conference-notes, correspondence, etc.
    - 8. Triest Conference 1989-general info about it.
    - 9. 1989-correspondence, etc.
    - 10. 1990-correspondence, etc.
    - 11. Okubo Spymposium 1990.
    - 12. Sakita '90-symposium in honor of Bunji Sakita's 60th birthday.
    - 13. Singapore-a meeting of the organizing committee.
    - 14. 1991-workshop on Electoweak Symmetry Breaking.
    - 15. Sudashan Workshop-scientific notes.
    - 16. 1992-correspondence to/from: Gaetano Scarpetta, Lillian Hoddeson, etc.
    - 17. 1993-correspondence concerning the Fifth International Symposium on "Neutrino Telescopes."
  - CONG-COV, including: (Box-folder C1-22)
    - 1. Contracts and grants-correspondence about the subject.
    - 2. Council of Graduate Schools in the U.S.
    - 3. Council of Scientific Society Presidents.
    - 4. Council on Foreign Relations.
  - COW-CZ, including: (Box-folder C1-23)
    - 1. CSSS-Center for the Study of Science in Society-correspondence from Arthur Donovan, etc.
    - 2. Cunningham Fellowships-correspondence from David Roselle.
  - D-DEO. (Box-folder C1-24)
  - Manpower-Manpower in the High Energy Physics, lists, correspondence. (Box-folder C1-25)
  - Subpanel on Non-Accelerator Particle Physics-listings; correspondence from J. Sandweiss. (Box-folder C1-26)
  - TACUP (DOE)-Technical Assessment Committee for University Programs-correspondence from Harold K. Ticho. (Box-folder C1-27)
  - Proposal Reviews-correspondence to/from: Robert L. Thews, P. K. Williams, etc. (Box-folder C1-28)
  - CRAY-correspondence concerning the CRAY X-MP machine from William A. Wallenmeyer, etc. (Box-folder C1-29)
  - RD&D-research and development correspondence to/from William Wallenmeyer, Notice ov Energy RD & D Project. (Box-folder C1-30)
- Box C2
  - Progress reports on DOE (Department of Energy) under the title Theory of Weak Interactions and Related Topics. (Box-folder C2-1)
  - Department of Energy (DOE)-correspondence dealing with progress reports and proposals. (Box-folder C2-2)
  - 1981-correspondence concerining the proposals for and extension of the DOE grant; revised budget, etc. (Box-folder C2-3)
  - 1982-correspondence concerning DOE grants, budgets, etc. (Box-folder C2-4)
  - 1983-correspondence about the budget, DOE progress, etc. (Box-folder C2-5)
  - Report-report on DOE, High Enery Physics. (Box-folder C2-6)
  - 1984-DOE Proposals, etc. (Box-folder C2-7)
  - 1985-Research proposals. (Box-folder C2-8)
  - 1986-Correspondence concerning research proposals. (Box-folder C2-9)
  - 1987-Correspondence concerning DOE proposals. (Box-folder C2-10)
  - DEQ-DN, including: (Box-folder C2-11)
    - 1. Development of Elementary Particle Physics-correspondence.
    - 2. DeWind Committee.
    - 3. Division of Particles and Fields (meeting).
  - DIRAC Price-correspondence. (Box-folder C2-12)
  - DO-DQ, including: (Box-folder C2-13)
    - 1. Donovan, A.-correspondence to/from.
    - 2. Doswald, H.-correspondence to/from.
  - DR-DZ-correspondence. (Box-folder C2-14)
  - E-EO, including: (Box-folder C2-15)
    - 1. Energy-Suggestions for a Phase-II National Energy Policy (1977), by William M. Brown and Herman Kahn.
    - 2. Enrico Fermi Award-correspondence concerning nominations.
    - 3. EPS-European Physical society-copies of paid membership checks.
  - EPSCOR-Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research. (Box-folder C2-16)
  - EQ-EZ-Eric Conferernce '79: bulletin, scientific notes. (Box-folder C2-17)
  - F.O.R.G.E.-correspondence concerning FORGE grants. (Box-folder C2-18)
  - F-FEDERATION-miscellaneous correspondence to/from Wolt Fabrycky, Clifton T. McLoed, etc. (Box-folder C2-19)
- Box D1
  - FEE-FERMI, including: (Box-folder D1-1)
    - 1. Miscellaneous correspondence from Feinberg, B. Feld, D. Feldman, etc.
    - 2. Fellowships-letters to tehe University of North Carolina, University of Michigan, etc.
    - 3. Miscellaneous correspondence form Farinholt, Feshback, etc.
  - Fermilab (Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory), including: (Box-folder D1-2)
    - 1. Newsletters, correspondence, etc.
  - FES-FQ, including: (Box-folder D1-3)
    - 1. Feynman-correspondence from R. P. Feynman.
    - 2. Miscellaneous correspondence to/from: H. Feshbach, S. Feuer, etc.
    - 3. Finn, D.-correspondence to/from David Finn.
    - 4. Miscellaneous correspondence to/from Fiorini, Fitzgerald, etc.
  - FR-FZ, including: (Box-folder D1-4)
    - 1. Florida State University-correspondence from Vasken Hagopin.
    - 2. Correspondence to/from V. Fraenckel, W. Fretter, etc.
  - G-GH, including: (Box-folder D1-5)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: J. Gammel, W. Gannett, etc.
    - 2. Geng-Dr. Chaoqiang Geng's correspondence, curriculum vitae, applications, etc.
  - GI-GN, including: (Box-folder D1-6)
    - 1. Correspondence to Alexander Giacco.
    - 2. Correspondence to/from R. Gibbs, T. Gilmer, etc.
    - 3. Glasgow Conference-program, correspondence, etc.
    - 4. Correspondence to/from: R. Glass, S. Glashow, etc.
    - 5. Correspondence to/from Nathan Glazer.
    - 6. Correspondence to/from Stephen Globus.
  - GO-GUF, including: (Box-folder D1-7)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from V. Goldanskii, M. Goldberg, etc.
    - 2. Gorbachev-Report on the Council Delegation Visit to the U.S.S.R.
    - 3. Correspondence to/from W. Gordon, I. Greenberg, etc.
    - 4. Correspondence to/from: F. Gonnenwein, Grenoble, etc.
    - 5. Correspondnece to V. Gribov.
    - 6. Correspondence to/from T. Griffith, F. Gross, etc.
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, including: (Box-folder D1-8)
    - 1. Fellowships, Fellowship programs 1981-1983, reports for 1979.
  - GUH-GZ, including: (Box-folder D1-9)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: D. Guinier, P. Gulmanelli, etc.
  - H-HD, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: W. Hass, H. Halban, etc.
  - Heineman Prize, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. Correspondence about the prize.
  - HEPAP, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. High Energy Physics Advisory Panel (HEPAP)-summer study and research programs.
  - HE-HON, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: C. Hebel, W. Helmreich, etc.
    - 2. Honor Program-VA Tech's University Honors Program.
    - 3. Honor System-VA Tech's Honor System-plagiarism, etc.
  - HOO-HUL, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. The Physical Society correspondence.
    - 2. Hotels-reservation, cancellation, and receipt.
    - 3. Correspondence to/from: C. Houska, J. Howard, etc.
  - Human Rights, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. Correspondence, pending cases, etc.
  - HUM-HZ, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Hubert Humphret, Henry Hurwitz, R. Huntoon, etc.
  - ICSU, including: (Box-folder D1-10)
    - 1. International Council of the Scientific Unions Program (ICSU). Advisory Committee for ICSU Propsal.
- Box D2
  - IUPAP (International Union of Pure and Applied Physics)-notebook of info.; news bulletins; minutes from meetings; articles; reports; correspondence. (Box-folder D2-1)
  - IUPAP-nominations for commission; info regarding the 17th General Assembly; correspondence; statutes; general report of '82; tentative agenda for the Meeting of the U.S. Liaison Committee for IUPAP. (Box-folder D2-2)
  - I-INT, including: (Box-folder D2-3)
    - 1. India-agenda to India; correspondence from L. S. Kothari, etc.
    - 2. IHEP-correspondence from Luke W. Mo; A. Abashian; etc.
    - 3. Institute for Advanced Study-list of visiting professors and long time members; newletters.
    - 4. International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA)-newsletters.
  - Institute of International Education (IIE) book: U.S. College Sponsored Programs Abroad; Annual Report 1978. (Box-folder D2-4)
  - Institute-notes and correspondence. (Box-folder D2-5)